Guide to the Samuel DuBois Cook Papers, 1949-2015 RL.11747
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Speeches, 1974-2002; 3
  - Professional Speeches, 5
    - Justice and Social Change in the Thought of Reinhold Niebuhr...., 1974 (Box 13)
    - Keynote: Carter G. Woodson Institute, 1982 Feb 27 (Box 11)
      "Beyond Tragedy" Challenges of the 80's and the Beloved Community of All of God's Children"
    - King, Commemoration of the Birthday of Martin Luther King Jr., 1977-1992; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - King, Ecumenical Service, 1988-1995; 10 folders (Box 11)
    - King, Is Martin Luther King Jr.'s Dream Irrelevant or Meaningless?, 1982, 1983; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - King, The Legacy and Significance of Martin Luther King Jr., 1974, 1976; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - King, Martin Luther Address, 1968 Jun 2 (Box 11)
      "Who and What Will Honor and Memorialize Martin Luther King?"
    - King, Martin Luther King Jr. and the Unfinished Task, 1987 Apr 4 (Box 11)
    - King, Memorial Concert, 1986-1997; 10 folders (Box 11)
    - King, Our Fleeting But Eternal Moment, 1987 Dec 13 (Box 11)
    - King, Reflections on Martin Luther King Jr., 1986, undated; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - King, Running for Mankind, 1973, May 12 (Box 11)
    - King, Seminar, 1998 Jan 19 (Box 11)
    - King, Spiritual Legacy, Undated (Box 11)
    - King, Ten Years After Memphis, 1978 Nov 10 (Box 11)
    - King, The Dream Yesterday, 1998 Jan 19 (Box 11)
    - King, What Is A Secret of the Greatness of Martin Luther King Jr.?, Undated (Box 11)
    - The Kingdom of God and the Uneasy Conscience, 1990 Mar 30 (Box 11)
      Touro Synagogue
    - The Lacrosse Tragedy and the Beloved Community at Duke, 2007 Feb 27 (Box 11)
    - Leiserson, Avery, Undated (Box 11)
    - Louisiana Annual Conference, 1977-1996; 9 folders (Box 11)
    - Mayor Bill Campbell, 1990-2001; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Mays, Benjamin E., 1976-1990; 5 folders (Box 11)
      Assorted Speeches
    - McCord, Lina H., 1985 Sep 19 (Box 11)
      "In Praise, Joy, Thanksgiving, and Celebration"
    - McGill, Ralph, 1979 Feb 26 (Box 11)
      "A Man of Great Decency"
    - McMain Magnet Secondary School, 1989 Jun 4 (Box 11)
    - The Meaning, Necessity, and Practicality of Forgiveness, 1975 Nov 30 (Box 11)
    - Meeting of Bishop Oden and the Cabinet of the LAC of the United Methodist Church, 1994 Mar 22 (Box 11)
      "Status and Overview of Dillard University"
    - Meeting with Mayor Barthelemy, 1990 Dec 10 (Box 11)
    - Memorial Services, 1976-1992; 24 folders (Box 11)
      Honorees Include: William E. Pullin, Dr. Herman H. Long, Walter E. Jordan, William Stuart Nelson, Dr. David Spitz, Dr. Kimuel Alonzo Huggins Jr., Howard Thurman, Henrietta Shivery Long, Frank Forbes, Frederick D. Hall, Dr. Benjamin E. Mays, Wilbur D. Moore, Albert W. Dent, Paul A. Harmon, Mary Murray Cook, Rita E. Miller Dargan, Dorothy Pleasant Handy, Oralee Baranco Mitchell, Orlando D. Wooden, Dr. Clifford R. Bryan, Victims of Earthquake in Kobe Japan, Dr. Broadus N. Butler, Dr. Mack J. Spears, Orlando D. Wooden, Dr. Crispus S. Gordon
    - Men's Day, 1980-2001; 4 folders (Box 11)
    - Metropolitan Area Committee, 1982-1986; 4 folders (Box 11)
    - Metropolitan Leadership Forum, 1996 Oct 9 (Box 11)
    - Miller, Dr Isaac H.; Blake, Dr. Elias; Carter, Dr. Hazo, 1987 Sep 16 (Box 11)
      Council of United Methodists Presidents' Commemorative Dinner
    - Minority Economic Development, 1978 Mar 28 (Box 11)
      "Is Political Power the Key to Black Economic Power, Freedom and Development?"
    - The Mission of Black Colleges: The Continuity of Duality and Multi-Dimensionality, 1992 Jan 29 (Box 11)
    - Mississippi Valley State University, 1996 Jan 11 (Box 11)
      "Shall We Give Up On the Ideal and Goal of the Beloved Community?"
    - The Moral Uses and Responsibilities of Colleges and Universities, 1983 Apr 21 (Box 11)
    - Morehouse College, 1979-1995, undated; 9 folders (Box 12)
    - Morial, 1982 Nov 20 (Box 12)
      "Introduction of Mayor Morial"
    - Morial, Ernest N., 1986 Apr 29 (Box 12)
      "Mayor Dutch Moral: Celebration and Thanksgiving"
    - Moss, Dr. Otis, 1984 May 13 (Box 12)
    - My Sister, Mabel, A Tough Act and Sister, Undated (Box 12)
    - NAACP, 1980-1995; 3 folders (Box 12)
    - National Alumni Association, 1983 May 28 (Box 12)
      "Black Colleges and the American Dream"
    - National Association of College and University Chaplains, 1984 Feb 27 (Box 12)
      "Liberal Education, Social Justice, and the Kingdom Not of This World"
    - National Association for Equality in Higher Education, Apr 28 (Box 12)
      "Black Colleges and Academic Success"
    - National Association of Negro Musicians, 1987 Aug 3 (Box 12)
      "The Negro Spiritual and the Kingdom Not of This World"
    - National Baptist Convention, 1978 Sep 6 (Box 12)
    - National Conference of Black Political Scientists, 1978 Apr 21 (Box 12)
      "The Politics of Black Higher Education"
    - National Conference on Minority Child Care and Family Issues, 1989 Jul 13,14; 2 folders (Box 12)
      "Where Do We Go From Here in Terms of Minority Child Care and Family Issues"; "Greetings and Welcome to the House Select Committee"
    - National Football Hall of Fame Distinguished American Award, 1989 Apr 26 (Box 12)
    - National Honor Society, 1986 Apr 17 (Box 12)
    - National Insurance Association, 1976 Jul 20 (Box 12)
    - National Urban League Conference, 1976, 1978; 2 folders (Box 12)
      "Black Representation in the American Political System: A Philosophical and Historical Overview"; "Is Political Power the Key to Black Economic Power, Freedom, and Development?"
    - Nebraska Wesleyan University Baccalaureate Address, 1991 May 18 (Box 12)
    - The Negro Spiritual and the Kingdom Not of this World, 1987 Aug 3 (Box 12)
    - Nelson, Dr. William Stuart, 1977 May 13 (Box 12)
      "Memorial Meditation and Reflection on the Life of William Stuart Nelson"
    - Newman School's First Martin Luther King Assembly, 1989 Jan 16 (Box 12)
    - New Orleans District Conference, 1975 Apr 20 (Box 12)
      "Greetings and Thanks to the New Orleans District"
    - New Orleans Federation of Churches Breakfast, 1982 May 20 (Box 12)
      "Giving: A Theology of Stewardship"; Contains Pamphlet
    - New Orleans Insurance Executive Council, 1975 May 8 (Box 12)
    - New Orleans Minority Business Seminar, 1982 Nov 20 (Box 12)
    - New Orleans Public Schools, 1995 May 8 (Box 12)
      "Rites of Passage Ceremony, Class of 1999"
    - Norris, Bishop Alfred L., 1992 Sep 20 (Box 12)
    - North American Federation of Temple Brotherhoods, 1997 Oct 30 (Box 12)
      "The Desperate Urgency of Inter-Faith Bridge-Building"
    - Notes on the Survival of Higher Education, 1978 Oct 25 (Box 12)
    - Nuclear Weapons and the Dark Future, 1984 Mar 14 (Box 12)
    - NULITES, 1996 Aug 10 (Box 12)
      Includes Program
    - Opening Statement: Opening of Multi-Purpose Complex, 1993 Oct 19 (Box 12)
      Samuel DuBois Cook Fine Arts and Communications Center
    - Opening Remarks, 1996 Mar 31 (Box 12)
      Rededication of, and "Open House" for Hearny Hall
    - Our Anguished, Tortured and Beloved South, 1976 May 27 (Box 12)
      "From Anti-Humanism to Humanism; From Despair to Hope"
    - Our Fleeting But Eternal Moment, 1975-1991; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Person, Citizen, and Southern Traditions: A Problem of Justice and Being, undated (Box 12)
    - Phillips. Pharisee and Publican. Self-Righteousness, undated (Box 12)
    - A Political Agenda for the South, 1979 Feb 17 (Box 12)
      "A Humanistic Vision and Commitment Beyond the Tragedy of Racism and Poverty"
    - The Politics of Black Higher Education, 1978 Apr 21 (Box 12)
    - Politics and the Future of Black Colleges, undated (Box 12)
    - The Political Process and Black Liberation: Old Myths and New Realities, undated (Box 12)
    - Prayer, 1976 Oct 7 (Box 12)
      American Council on Education
    - Prayer, 1996 Mar 5 (Box 12)
      Council of Presidents
    - Prayer: Christmas Dinner, 1977, 1979 (Box 12)
    - Prayer: College Fund?UNCF, 1997 Jun 8 (Box 12)
    - Prayer: Duke Board of Trustees, 1993 Feb 26 (Box 12)
    - Prayer: Lord Help Me Live, undated (Box 12)
    - Prayer of Rededication, 1996 Nov 3 (Box 12)
      Celebration of 150th Anniversary 0of the American Missionary Association
    - Preface to 1995-6 Higley Int'l Sunday School (Box 12)
    - President's Message, 1992 Nov 22 (Box 12)
      "What A Day! The Honoring of Bishop and Mrs. William Bryant Oden and Louisiana United Methodism"
    - Press Conferences, 1983-1993; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Prologue: The Supreme Tragedy of Illegal Drugs, undated (Box 12)
    - Providence Baptist Church Annual Educational Scholarship Banquet, 1995 May 6 (Box 12)
      "We Are All Involved"
    - PUSH, 1980 Jul 16 (Box 12)
      "Introduction of Reb Jesse Louis Jackson"
    - Quality Public Education, 1988 Feb 9 (Box 12)
      Press Conference on Governor-Elect Roemer's and his Transition Advisory Panel
    - Quotations Given by Rabbi David S. Goldstein, undated (Box 12)
    - Racism and Sexism: A Double Tragedy Issuing From a Single Source, Apr 27-29 (Box 12)
    - Reaffirmation Committee, 1989 Mar 21, 23; 2 folders (Box 12)
      Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (SACS)
    - Reflections on the Bennie Service Award, 1995 Feb 18 (Box 12)
      Morehouse College
    - Reflections of a Black Man on His Pilgrimage to and the Study of Israel, 1977 Mar 1 (Box 12)
      University Assembly
    - Reflections on the Vigil, 1973 Feb 15 (Box 12)
    - Regional CICALS Workshop III, 1995 Nov 10 (Box 12)
    - Remarks: This is a Day the Lord Hath Made, 1991 Mar 22 (Box 12)
      Groundbreaking Ceremony for the Fine Arts and Communications Center
    - Report of the Mayor's Advisory Committee on Charter Revision, 1991 Apr 22 (Box 12)
    - Research and Scholarship: An Intellectual, Moral, and Social Imperative, 1982 Mar 25 (Box 12)
      Department of Political Science, Atlanta University
    - Response to Honor, 1984 Feb 12 (Box 12)
      Honored by the Black Chorale; contains handwritten notes
    - Resolution, 1983 Oct 22 (Box 12)
      Bishop J. Kenneth Shamblin
    - A Resolution of Appreciation to Dr. Robert E. Hayes Sr., 1986 Nov 16 (Box 12)
    - Resolution on Dr. Homer C. McEwen, 1985 Oct 19 (Box 12)
    - Rev. Lawrence T. Evans, 1992 Sep 22 (Box 12)
    - The Rucker Family Reunion, 1995 Jul 2 (Box 12)
      "The Deep Beauty, Glory, and Responsibility of the Black Family"
    - The Scripture Reading, undated (Box 12)
    - SDC Summer Scholars Conference, 1999, undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - SDC Society, 2002 Feb 12 (Box 12)
    - The Season of Remembrance, undated (Box 12)
    - Second Annual Breakfast of Champions Award Ceremony, 1991 Apr 19 (Box 12)
      "Corporate Volunteer Action Awards (VIA)"
    - Selected Ethical Responsibilities of Colleges and Universities, 1992 Mar 23 (Box 12)
    - Shades of Black in Many Colors, 1992 Feb 22 (Box 12)
    - Shall We Give Up On the Ideal and Goal of the Beloved Community, 1994-1998; 5 folders (Box 12)
    - Shall We Give Up On Dr. King's Dream of the Beloved Community, 2004, undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Shall We Turn Back?, 1985,1992, undated; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Shamblin, Bishop J. Kenneth, 1976, 1983; 2 folders (Box 12)
      "Welcome to Bishop Shamblin"; "Resolution"
    - Social Justice in America, undated (Box 12)
    - Some Issues in Higher Education, undated (Box 12)
    - The Southern Historical Association, 1982 Nov 3 (Box 12)
      "Beyond the Tragedy and Tyranny of Racism to the Beloved Community of All of God's Children"
    - The Southern Political Science Association and the Perennial Struggle for Human Decency, 1978 Nov 10 (Box 12)
    - Southhall, Dr. Geneva Handy, 1978 Apr 20 (Box 12)
      Honors Day Convocation
    - Southwide Conference for Negro Elected Officials, 1968 Dec 11-14 (Box 12)
      "From Subject and Victim to Citizen and Public Official: An Historical Sketch of the Negro in the Southern Political Process"; Duke University
    - Spelman College Convocation, 1986 Jan 23 (Box 12)
      "What is the Ultimate Meaning of Being a Responsible Person?"
    - The Struggle for Racial Justice, undated (Box 12)
    - Testimonial Dinners, 1973,1976; 2 folders (Box 12)
      "Reflections and Joys of the Mountaintop"; "Dr. E. B. Williams: A Great Teacher"
    - Thompson, Dr. Daniel C., 1992, undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Thurman, Sue Bailey, 1997 May 15 (Box 12)
      Interment Service
    - Times-Picayune Editorial Staff Press Conference, 1989 (Box 12)
      "Mayor's 1989 Charter Revision Committee"
    - Torch of Liberty Award Dinner, 1979 Dec 2 (Box 12)
      "This I Do Believe"
    - Touro Synagogue, 1990 Mar 30 (Box 12)
      "The Kingdom of God and the Uneasy Conscience"
    - A Tribute to Dr. A. L. Davis Jr., 1975 Feb 25 (Box 12)
    - Trotter, Dr. F. Thomas, 1987 Oct 14 (Box 12)
      "In Appreciation"
    - United Methodist-Related Black Colleges and Their Mission, 1981 Sep 24 (Box 12)
    - UNCF, 1974-1993; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Unidentified Speech, undated (Box 12)
    - Vision and Humanistic Learning, undated (Box 12)
    - Vision and Method in Political Science, 1973 Nov 2 (Box 12)
    - Voter Registration Rally, 1995 Aug 22 (Box 12)
      "Jesse Louis Jackson"
    - Wake for Dr. Crispus S. Gordon, 1992 Apr 22 (Box 12)
    - We Are All Involved, 1995 May 6 (Box 12)
      Annual Educational Scholarship Banquet at Providence Baptist Church
    - Wedding: Ora Montgomery and Charles Darden, 1981 Apr 4 (Box 12)
    - Wedding: Rebecca Flot and Warren Bell Jr., 1983 Mar 4 (Box 12)
    - Weiss Award Dinner: Acceptance Remarks, 1989 Nov 9 (Box 12)
    - What Is A Meaningful Life?, 1976-1983; 3 folders (Box 12)
    - What Is the Role of Moral Idealism in This Tragic World?, 1978 May 25 (Box 12)
    - When Your Dream Dies, 1979-1981; 5 folders (Box 12)
    - Where Do We Go From Here?, 1998; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Williams, Dr. Henry M: A Man of Thought and Action, 1986 Aug 18 (Box 12)
    - The Wisdom De Profundis of Benjamin E. Mays, Black Colleges, and the Good Life, 1994 Oct 7 (Box 12)
    - Yesterday, Today, Tomorrow, and The Kingdom Not of This World, 1980 Nov 14 (Box 12)
      Founder's Day on Union Baptist Theological Seminary